{
  "category": "Oceanography",
  "difficulty": "hard",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which term describes the salinity, temperature, and density gradients or layers in the ocean?",
      "options": [
        "Isothermal",
        "Isobaric",
        "Halocline",
        "Pycnocline"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Pycnocline",
      "id": "CF8C2E2D-CAE8-4DA9-B132-7BE4059960A8"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name for the region in the water column which sees the maximum rate of decrease in temperature with increasing depth?",
      "options": [
        "Thermocline",
        "Halocline",
        "Pycnocline",
        "Epipelagic zone"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Thermocline",
      "id": "708F5BC9-CE7C-48F2-915C-E2C5A9293CB1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name for the seafloor feature that is created where an oceanic plate is subducting beneath another plate?",
      "options": [
        "Mid-ocean ridge",
        "Abyssal plain",
        "Oceanic trench",
        "Continental rise"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Oceanic trench",
      "id": "54FF0D09-A40F-4F3F-9D2F-B12939ECA1A2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What drives the thermohaline circulation in the world's oceans?",
      "options": [
        "Tidal forces",
        "Surface wind",
        "Differences in temperature and salinity",
        "Ocean currents"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Differences in temperature and salinity",
      "id": "79563077-159B-4D85-90D8-4AE89EEF9FC3"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which oceanic zone represents the deepest part of the ocean, below 6000 meters?",
      "options": [
        "Bathypelagic Zone",
        "Mesopelagic Zone",
        "Abyssopelagic Zone",
        "Hadopelagic Zone"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Hadopelagic Zone",
      "id": "683ECF70-B985-4811-B78B-7FF1494841D8"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which layer of the ocean is characterized by constant low temperature, high pressure, low oxygen, and minimal nutrient levels?",
      "options": [
        "Epipelagic layer",
        "Mesopelagic layer",
        "Bathypelagic layer",
        "Abyssopelagic layer"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Abyssopelagic layer",
      "id": "BFE51FC8-84FD-447D-BBA4-44AC5F715F51"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of marine ecosystem is characterized by areas of open water that may be periodically covered by land due to fluctuating water levels?",
      "options": [
        "Estuarine",
        "Intertidal",
        "Benthic",
        "Pelagic"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Intertidal",
      "id": "A7F09EA2-64BC-4278-8AD6-B819F1957C74"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which principle states that the ratio of the concentration of a chemical in an organism to the concentration of the chemical in the surrounding environment is constant across different levels of biological organization?",
      "options": [
        "Principle of Constant Proportions",
        "Biot-Savart Law",
        "Dittmar's Principle",
        "Principle of Biological Magnification"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Principle of Biological Magnification",
      "id": "87825D87-6706-4FF1-8B7E-969D48A5A81B"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the amount of solid salt in seawater, usually expressed in parts per thousand?",
      "options": [
        "Salinity",
        "Density",
        "Conductivity",
        "Alkalinity"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Salinity",
      "id": "4E7D928A-57A3-4C9E-9662-D14762F6B2EC"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Ekman spiral describe in oceanography?",
      "options": [
        "The shape of wave patterns",
        "The direction of deep ocean currents",
        "The change in wind direction with height",
        "The effect of the Coriolis effect on wind-driven ocean currents"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "The effect of the Coriolis effect on wind-driven ocean currents",
      "id": "0C217682-19EE-4F30-914E-DBC419C70DCF"
    }
  ]
}
